Aman Agarwal

College Station, Texas | (979) 985-7122 | aman.agarwal2189@gmail.com | github.com/amanagarwal2189

SUMMARY

Graduate student developing skills in a techno-management environment to excel in field of software engineering. Have a solid work experience of 4 years in Agile software development environment creating cutting edge retail banking applications. Proven skills in object oriented development, product delivery and integration and conducting POCs for critical requirements.

EDUCATION

Texas A&M University College Station, Texas

Master of Science in Management Information Systems, GPA: 4.00

May 2017

Vellore Institute of Technology

Vellore, India

Bachelor of Technology in Information Technology, GPA: 3.93

May 2011

SKILLS

Programming Languages: Java, Python, SQL, XML

Technologies: HTML5, JavaScript, CSS, JSON, Dojo, AJAX

Database: DB2, Oracle 9i/10g/11g, MySQL

Frameworks: Numpy, Pandas, Hadoop, Hibernate

Tools: Eclipse, Jupyter, Maven, Github, JIRA, MS Visio, Scriptella

EXPERIENCE

Misys Bangalore, India

Software Engineer

December 2014 – July 2015

- Liaised with business teams for requirement gathering, efforts estimation and project scheduling.
- Achieved 200% increase in transaction posting rate to revamp retail core-banking transactions by redesigning process flows, refactoring Java code of strategic functionalities and optimizing JDBC-SQL queries.
- Digitized queue management and thus improved customer experience at retail bank branches by developing kiosk based token system using MVC framework with Java, Hibernate, JavaScript and HTML5.

Associate Software Engineer

July 2011 - November 2014

- Migrated applet-based client of core banking software to faster web interface developed using AJAX, Dojo and JQuery
- Developed ETL data script creation mechanism using Scriptella for 24x7 availability and synchronization of transaction system at retail bank branches.
- Enhanced operational efficiency by 20% at retail bank branches by automating transfer of customer entered transaction data from Queue Management System to core-banking system.
- Automated unit-test case generation by developing tool on Java thus improving code coverage by 35%.
- Performed proof of concept using JavaScript to capture and manipulate data from magnetic-card readers.

PROJECTS

Rental Prediction Model

• Formulated a model using Python's Numpy and Pandas libraries to predict housing prices using Regression Analysis based on 5 different factors which might affect the housing prices. Currently enhancing this model to accommodate 19 factors.

Weather Prediction Accuracy Analyzer

September 2015-December 2015

• Developed web-application to perform data analysis using Hadoop Map-Reduce Framework on 5 GB of data collected from various weather reporting websites. Generated comparative prediction accuracy charts on web-based user interface.

Movie Rating Analysis

September 2015-December 2015

 Developed a model to analyze dataset to identify trends and cross reference movie-liking pattern of the customers of Movie-Lens website.

VITZaz – Collaboration platform for university

July 2010 - December 2010

July 2016 - Present

 Developed application on Java supported by DB2 database to provide an interaction platform between students and faculty members. Used JSP, HTML and CSS to construct the web interface.

LEADERSHIP

Business Information Technology Students, Texas A&M University

April 2016 - Till Date

VP - Operations

FunFusion for Social Ventures at Misys

October 2014 - June 2015

Co-founder

- Motivated 200 employees to volunteer for events organized by NPOs to benefit people with disabilities.
- Arranged orphanage and hospice-care visits and cleanliness drives to foster socially conscious workplace.